export interface Question {
  question: string;
  options: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
}

export const questions: Question[] = [
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name is a combination of two words 'kanta' and 'bakilid', meaning 'sing' and 'hill.'",
    options: ['Cantomimbo', 'Cantalid', 'Candasig', 'Cogon'],
    correctAnswer: 'Cantalid',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name comes from the term 'timbo,' a meeting point of two brooks, one from Antequera and the other from Balilihan.",
    options: ['Cantomimbo', 'Cantalid', 'Cogon', 'Datag'],
    correctAnswer: 'Cantomimbo',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay was once called 'Nueva Cuta' meaning 'new area' and got its current name from a long grass that grows abundantly.",
    options: ['Candasig', 'Cogon', 'Cabad', 'Datag'],
    correctAnswer: 'Cogon',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name means 'vast plains' and is where the sitio 'Bay sa Iring,' the first establishment of Balilihan, is located.",
    options: ['Datag', 'Dorol', 'Del Rosario', 'San Isidro'],
    correctAnswer: 'Datag',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This area is named after the town's patron saint and comprises four poblacion barangays.",
    options: ['San Isidro', 'Del Carmen', 'Santo Ni単o', 'Tagustusan'],
    correctAnswer: 'Del Carmen',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name comes from the term 'bawok,' a fine substance extracted from a plant called 'patikan' that easily burns when dried.",
    options: ['Baucan', 'Boctol', 'Boyog', 'Maslog'],
    correctAnswer: 'Baucan',
  },
  {
    question: "Early settlers named this barangay after a spring and water source called 'Boto'.",
    options: ['Boctol', 'Boyog', 'Baucan', 'San Roque'],
    correctAnswer: 'Boctol',
  },
  {
    question:
      'This barangay got its name from a hill inhabited by bees, a source of honey in the past.',
    options: ['Sal-ing', 'Boyog', 'Tagustusan', 'Candasig'],
    correctAnswer: 'Boyog',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name comes from the term 'gakabad-kabad' which describes a striking motion to and fro.",
    options: ['Candasig', 'Cogon', 'Cabad', 'Maslog'],
    correctAnswer: 'Cabad',
  },
  {
    question: "This barangay's name comes from the term 'kadasig' meaning 'lively'.",
    options: ['Cabad', 'Candasig', 'Cantomimbo', 'Boctol'],
    correctAnswer: 'Candasig',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name comes from a tree called 'agasa' that was once abundant and became a landmark with the phrase 'adto sa agasa'.",
    options: ['Sagasa', 'San Isidro', 'Del Carmen', 'Tagustusan'],
    correctAnswer: 'Sagasa',
  },
  {
    question: "This barangay's name comes from a tree whose fruits attract birds called 'iling'.",
    options: ['Boctol', 'Sal-ing', 'Maslog', 'Del Rosario'],
    correctAnswer: 'Sal-ing',
  },
  {
    question:
      'This barangay, formerly a sitio of Sal-ing called Luinab, got its current name from a chapel dedicated to Saint Isidore.',
    options: ['San Roque', 'San Isidro', 'Santo Ni単o', 'Candasig'],
    correctAnswer: 'San Isidro',
  },
  {
    question:
      'This barangay, one of ten newly created barrios in Hanopol, was named after its patron saint and served as a concentration camp during World War II.',
    options: ['San Roque', 'Santo Ni単o', 'Del Rosario', 'Baucan'],
    correctAnswer: 'Santo Ni単o',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay's name comes from a term describing the process of rolling logs down a cliff tied to cables.",
    options: ['Tagustusan', 'Dorol', 'Hanopol', 'Sagasa'],
    correctAnswer: 'Tagustusan',
  },
  {
    question:
      'This barangay is named after the second patron of Hanopol, the Virgin of the Holy Rosary.',
    options: ['Del Carmen', 'Del Rosario', 'Datag', 'San Roque'],
    correctAnswer: 'Del Rosario',
  },
  {
    question: "This barangay's name comes from a tree known for its 'kapok' or 'doldol' fibers.",
    options: ['Dorol', 'Datag', 'Cantomimbo', 'Maslog'],
    correctAnswer: 'Dorol',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay, once called 'Pekin,' meaning 'to swing,' got its current name from a strong vine that attracted the Americans.",
    options: ['Hanopol', 'Magsija', 'Maslog', 'Sagasa'],
    correctAnswer: 'Hanopol',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay, formerly called 'Canaway,' got its current name from the term 'sija' meaning to separate good seeds from bad ones.",
    options: ['Sagasa', 'Magsija', 'Tagustusan', 'San Roque'],
    correctAnswer: 'Magsija',
  },
  {
    question:
      "This barangay, once called 'Bahaybahay,' got its current name from a spring called 'Masog' known for its strong water flow.",
    options: ['Maslog', 'Boctol', 'Del Carmen', 'San Isidro'],
    correctAnswer: 'Maslog',
  },
];
